Finding Aid for Einar Kvaran Papers, 1980-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Einar Kvaran Papers 1980-1992
Kvaran, Einar.
1 linear ft.
Employee of the Michigan Federation of Food Cooperatives, The People's Wherehouse, Ann Arbor, Michigan; also union steward for the Industrial Workers of the World, Local 660. Reports, memoranda, notes, policies, and other papers relating to his work at the cooperative, and to union work and labor negotiations.
0144 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mr. Kvaran (donor no. 8960 ) and came to the library in May 2000.
The collection is open for research.
Einar Kvaran worked in the warehouse at the People's Wherehouse Food Co-Op. Following the unionization of its work force, Mr. Kvaran became a steward in the Industrial Workers of the World, Local 660.
The Kvaran papers are a rich source for information about the operation and unionization of the food co-op. The collection has been subdivided into two series: Michigan Federation of Food Co-op's The People's Wherehouse and The People's Wherehouse IWW Local 660. The first series contains information about the day-to-day operations of the warehouse and the eventual demise of the co-op. The latter series contains information about the union formed by the workers of the PWC. Included are the contract negotiations of the union, the by-laws and information about the legal battle between the Local 660 and the PWC management over unfair labor negotiations.
Subjects:
Cooperative societies--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Kvaran, Einar.; Labor unions--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Michigan Federation of Food Cooperatives.; People's Wherehouse.; Industrial Workers of the World. Detroit-Ann Arbor Branch.
- Michigan Federation of Food Co-ops The People's Wherehouse
  - 1987 Annual Report (Box 1)
  - Board of Director's File (Box 1)
  - Branch Council File (Box 1)
  - Buy-out Offers (Box 1)
  - Co-Op Policies (Box 1)
  - DSC (Box 1)
  - Evaluations (Box 1)
  - Finance Department (Box 1)
  - Grievances (Box 1)
  - Heath Insurance (Box 1)
  - Inventory Reports (Box 1)
  - Labor (Box 1)
  - Management (Box 1)
  - Management Reports (Box 1)
  - Memos to Staff (Box 1)
  - Michigan Milling Co-Op (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Organizational Booklet (Box 1)
  - Organizational Chart (Box 1)
  - The People's Business (Box 1)
  - Personnel (Box 1)
  - Product and Policy Notebook, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Steering Committee (Box 1)
  - Survey Committee (Box 1)
  - Warehouse Department (Box 1)
- People's Wherehouse Co-op IWW Local 660
  - Negotiation File, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Compensation Ideas (Box 1)
  - Contract Negotiation, 1986-1988 (Box 1)
  - Contract Negotiation, 1989-1992 (Box 1)
  - Court Settlement (Box 1)
  - Future Negotiation Topics (Box 1)
  - IWW Startup (Box 1)
  - Labor Contact, 1989-1992 (Box 1)
  - Labor Contact University Cellar, Inc., 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 1)
  - National Labor Relations Board (Box 1)
  - Negotiation Committee Notes, 1983-1984, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Negotiation Committee Notes, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - University Cellar Contract (Box 1)
  - Union Business Meeting Notes (Box 1)
  - Union Busting (Box 1)
  - Union Bylaws (Box 1)
  - Union Certificate (Box 1)
  - Union Memos to BOD (Box 1)
  - Union Negotiation - Reopening of contract, April-October 1989 (Box 1)
  - Union Notices (Box 1)
  - Union Reports to Members (Box 1)